♪You crossed the sea of ​​stars and came with light♪
♪เธอข้ามผ่านหมู่ดวงดาว มาพร้อมกับแสงสว่าง♪
♪My heart is like the dust, and I couldn't bear to stain the hemline♪
♪หัวใจฉันเปรียบเหมือนฝุ่น ไม่อยากแปดเปื้อนกระโปรงของเธอ♪
♪To love in a different way, the fireworks are in the stars' good graces♪
♪ความรักที่ไม่เหมือนใคร ดอกไม้ไฟที่ดวงดาวยังชายตามอง♪
♪I turn around and realize that my heart is empty ♪
♪หันกลับมาจึงเข้าใจ ดวงใจได้ขาดหายไป♪
♪I miss the overflowing galaxy surging into the sea♪
♪ความคิดถึงท่วมท้นจักรวาล เอ่อล้นจนเต็มท้องทะเล♪
♪Even the fireworks desire to give the stars a future♪
♪ดอกไม้ไฟอยากเป็นที่พึ่งพิงให้ดวงดาว♪
♪As long as you are around♪
♪ขอเพียงแค่มีเธออยู่♪
♪Even the fireworks fear to bloom♪
♪ดอกไม้ไฟกลัวจะสว่างแล้วดับสูญ♪
♪Looking at you, the light in your eyes dimmed♪
♪มองดูนัยน์ตาของเธอ แสงไฟค่อย ๆ เลือนหาย♪
♪I laughed at myself and that I deserve it ♪
♪ทำได้แต่สมน้ำหน้าตัวเอง♪
♪My heart skips a beat, but I'm afraid I'm not worthy of the future that you desire♪
♪ฉันใจสั่น♪
=You Are My Glory=
=ดุจดวงดาวเกียรติยศ=
=Episode 17=
=ตอนที่ 17=
(One day before New Year, Xi'an)
(คืนก่อนปีใหม่ เมืองซีอาน)
I'm really feeling the vibe of New Year in Xi'an.
ช่วงปีใหม่ซีอานครึกครื้นเชียว
Look, it's so beautiful.
ดูสิ สวยจัง
Tomorrow,
พรุ่งนี้
in Chongqing,
ที่ฉงชิ่ง
there will be another road show.
มีโรดโชว์อีกครั้งหนึ่ง
On New Year's Day the day after tomorrow,
พรุ่งนี้วันขึ้นปีใหม่
your movie will officially be released.
เปิดตัวภาพยนตร์อย่างเป็นทางการ
We'll be flying to Beijing to attend the premiere.
เราจะบินไปปักกิ่งร่วมงานรอบปฐมทัศน์
Afterwards, you have two other road shows
หลังจากนั้นยังมีโรดโชว์อีกสองครั้ง
in Wuhan
ที่อู่ฮั่น
and Nanjing.
กับหนานจิง
Nanjing is close to Shanghai.
หนานจิงอยู่ไม่ไกลเซี่ยงไฮ้
Do you want to go back and rest a bit?
จะแวะกลับไปพักหน่อยไหม
After getting busy with your next schedule,
เดี๋ยวงานจะค่อนข้างยุ่ง
you won't have time to go back anymore.
จะไม่มีเวลากลับไปแล้วนะ
What activities are scheduled next?
หลังจากนี้เรายังมีงานอะไรอีกบ้างเหรอ
A few interviews,
สัมภาษณ์สองสามที่
a magazine shoot,
ถ่ายนิตยสาร
and a shoot for an advertisement.
แล้วก็ถ่ายโฆษณาอีกตัว
Before Spring Festival, the platform
ก่อนตรุษจีนทางแพลตฟอร์ม
has a few awarding ceremonies
ยังมีพิธีมอบรางวัลอีกสองสามงาน
that you must attend,
ที่เราต้องเข้าร่วม
but they're all in Beijing.
แต่อยู่ที่ปักกิ่งหมดเลย
I won't go back to Shanghai then.
งั้นก็ไม่ต้องกลับเซี่ยงไฮ้หรอก
I'll fly directly to Beijing.
บินตรงไปปักกิ่งเลย
Okay.
ได้
We have time for the Spring Festival Gala
งานคืนฉลองวันตรุษจีน
on the first day of the lunar new year.
พอจัดเวลาได้
Let's attend then.
เราไปร่วมงานกันด้วยเนอะ
Is the schedule for filming on the set of Mr. Li's movie confirmed?
หนังของผู้กำกับหลี่ กำหนดวันเข้ากองหรือยัง
The fifth day of the lunar new year
ห้าวันหลังตรุษจีน
is the time for the table read and test shoot.
ซ้อมอ่านบทเทสกล้อง
And the eighth day of the lunar new year is when you will officially start shooting.
แล้วอีกสามวันถ่ายจริง
If there is some work
งั้นงานบางอย่าง
that can be done before going to the film set,
ที่จัดการได้ก่อนเข้ากอง
let's do them.
ก็เคลียร์ให้เรียบร้อยก่อนเลยนะ
I don't want to keep taking leaves while filming.
ฉันไม่อยากเข้ากองแล้วต้องลาบ่อย ๆ
Okay.
ได้
By the way,
เอ่อนี่
there's an event in April
ช่วงเมษามีอยู่งานหนึ่ง
that I think you'll be interested in.
ฉันคิดว่าเธอน่าจะสนใจ
What is it?
อะไรเหรอ
April 24th
วันที่ยี่สิบสี่เมษายน
is Space Day.
เป็นวันอวกาศ
It's probably because you posted something
น่าจะเพราะเครื่องฟอกอากาศ เทคโนโลยีอวกาศ
about the aerospace tech air purifier for civilian use
ที่เธอโพสต์ไปตอนนั้น
so the organizer invited you
ผู้จัดงานเชิญเธอ
to join their gala.
เข้าร่วมงานเลี้ยงกลางคืนด้วย
If you come back
พอฉันไปแล้ว
after I leave,
ตอนนายกลับบ้านมา
I won't be here to give you
ก็คงไม่เจอการต้อนรับอย่างอบอุ่นอย่างฉัน
a passionate welcome anymore.
รอนายอยู่ที่บ้านแล้วนะ
Don't miss me.
อย่าคิดถึงกันล่ะ
I'm going on a business trip for a month soon.
เดี๋ยวฉันก็ต้องไปทำงานเมืองอื่นอีกหนึ่งเดือน
I don't have time to think of you.
ไม่มีเวลาคิดถึงนายหรอก
Can you show me some respect?
เห็นแก่หน้าฉันบ้างไม่ได้หรือไง
I may not know what exactly happened
ถึงฉันจะไม่รู้ว่านายกับปุยฝ้าย
between you and Cotton,
มีเรื่องอะไรกัน
but who are you?
แต่นายเป็นใคร
You're our idol.
นายเป็นเทพถูของพวกเราเลยนะ
You shouldn't live this way.
นายไม่ควรเป็นแบบนี้
Come on.
ไปเถอะ
I'll see you off.
ฉันไปส่ง
(Paiods Hotel)
(โรงแรม PAIODS)
- It must have been hard on you. - Thank you.
- ขอบคุณนะคะ - ขอบคุณค่ะ
Bye.
บ๊ายบาย
What do you think about the Space Day Gala?
งานเลี้ยงกลางคืนวันอวกาศว่ายังไง
I must give them a reply.
ฉันต้องตอบเขาแล้วนะ
Sure, why not?
ไปสิ ทำไมจะไม่ไปล่ะ
I'm honored to be invited.
นี่ถือว่าให้เกียรติฉันนี่นา
Okay.
ได้
I'll say yes to them then.
งั้นฉันตอบรับไปเลยนะ
I think this is quite good.
ฉันรู้สึกว่าเรื่องนี้ดีมากเลย
It's quite positive for your image.
เป็นภาพลักษณ์ที่ดูดีเลย
Besides,
อีกอย่าง
you might see Mr. Yu there.
ไม่แน่อาจได้เจออาจารย์อวี๋ก็ได้
Mr. Yu is so talented.
อาจารย์อวี๋เก่งขนาดนั้น
Perhaps he'll be a special guest or something.
อาจจะเป็นแขกรับเชิญก็ได้
Maybe.
ไม่แน่หรอก
At the celebration party last time,
งานฉลองแมตช์บันเทิงคราวก่อน
Mr. Yu didn't attend.
อาจารย์อวี๋ก็ไม่มา
If you have time later on,
ไว้เธอมีเวลา
treat Mr. Yu to a meal.
ชวนอาจารย์อวี๋ไปเลี้ยงข้าวด้วยนะ
We'll see.
ค่อยว่ากันเถอะ
My luggage.
กระเป๋า
Here.
นี่
Good night.
กู๊ดไนท์
Get some rest.
อย่านอนดึกนะ
- Good night.
- กู๊ดไนท์
♪Looking back in time and meeting the past again♪
♪ย้อนไปในกาลเวลา ได้พบอดีตอีกครั้ง♪
♪I write down my greetings for you in my heart♪
♪สิ่งที่บันทึกไว้ในใจ คือคำทักทายที่ติดค้างเธอ♪
♪Trying to piece together the reason for my longing♪
♪ลองนึกคิดถึง เหตุที่ทำให้ห่วงหา♪
♪It's the look in your eyes at a moment in my memories♪
♪คือสายตาของเธอในบางความทรงจำของฉัน♪
♪How long have you been alone in the crowd♪
♪ทางเดินผู้คนพลุกพล่าน เธอเดียวดายมานานเท่าไร♪
♪I'm used to drifting in the starry sky and the universe♪
♪ในห้วงอวกาศ ฉันลอยล่องอย่างคุ้นชิน♪
♪At the place where two worlds converge♪
♪ณ จุดนัดพบของโลกทั้งสอง♪
♪Can I hold your hand tightly♪
♪ฉันขอกุมมือของเธอไว้ได้ไหม♪
♪Today can we agree♪
♪วันนี้เรานัดกันได้หรือไม่♪
♪For me to tell you everything♪
♪ให้ฉันพูดให้เธอฟังทีละคำ♪
♪The questions I want to answer♪
♪คำตอบของคำถามนั้น ที่ฉันอยากบอกเธอ♪
♪In the sea of people♪
♪คือท่ามกลางผู้คน♪
♪I turned around and returned to a familiar scene♪
♪หันหลังกลับสู่ความคุ้นชิน♪
♪For your sake♪
♪คือฉันคนนี้♪
♪I'm back in the light♪
♪ที่ยังคงเก็บเวลาไว้เพื่อเธอ♪
♪Today can you feel it♪
♪วันนี้รับรู้ได้ไหม♪
♪The stars in the sky can attest♪
♪ดวงดาวเต็มฟ้าเป็นพยาน♪
♪That you're the one I want to find♪
♪เธอคือคนนั้น ที่ฉันอยากให้กลับคืน♪
(Yixing Station)
(สถานีอี๋ซิง)
♪In my dream♪
♪สิ่งที่รอคอย ณ จุดเริ่มแห่งความฝัน♪
♪Carved in my memories♪
♪สิ่งที่ทำให้ฉันจดจำไม่ลืมเลือนหาย♪
♪Is your courage♪
♪คือความหาญกล้าของเธอ♪
Coming.
มาแล้วจ้า
Mom.
แม่ครับ
Yu Tu.
อวี๋ถู
Why are you home?
ลูกกลับมาได้ยังไงเนี่ย
Dear.
เหล่าอวี๋
Hurry, our son is home.
มานี่เร็ว ลูกกลับมาแล้ว
Dad.
พ่อครับ
Didn't you just come back in October?
เพิ่งกลับมาตอนเดือนตุลา
Why are you back again?
ทำไมกลับมาอีกแล้วล่ะ
I'll go on a business trip for a month soon.
เดี๋ยวผมต้องไปทำงานต่างเมืองอีกหนึ่งเดือน
I'm not sure how the signal is there,
ไม่รู้ว่าที่นั่นมีสัญญาณหรือเปล่า
so I came home for a visit.
ก็เลยกลับบ้านสักหน่อย
For New Year's Eve this year,
งั้นคืนตรุษจีนปีนี้
will you be able to make it home?
ก็กลับมาไม่ได้ล่ะสิ
Yes.
กลับได้ครับ
That's good. Great.
กลับได้ก็เยี่ยมเลย เยี่ยม
That's great.
เยี่ยมไปเลย
I'll go and buy some cooked food.
เดี๋ยวพ่อไปซื้อกับข้าวก่อนนะ
Why?
ซื้อกับข้าวอะไรกัน
Our son is back.
ลูกชายกลับมาทั้งที
He must eat freshly-cooked food.
ต้องกินของทำใหม่ ๆ
Buy his favorites.
ซื้ออย่างที่ลูกชอบกิน
Shrimp, fish,
กุ้ง ปลา
and chicken. Buy them all.
แล้วก็ไก่ ซื้อมาให้หมดเลย
Okay, I got it.
โอเค รู้แล้วน่า
Come on.
เดี๋ยวมา ๆ
Let me take a look at you.
แม่ดูหน่อยซิ
Why have you grown thinner again?
ทำไมผอมอีกแล้วเนี่ย
Weren't you eating properly?
ไม่ค่อยได้กินข้าวใช่ไหมเนี่ย
I've been eating quite well.
กินครับแม่
You brat.
เจ้าลูกคนนี้
Here you go.
มาแล้ว
Stir-fried shredded potatoes.
มันฝรั่งเส้น
Here.
นี่
Drink some yogurt.
กินโยเกิร์ตหน่อย
Youngsters nowadays like to drink this.
วัยรุ่นสมัยนี้ชอบกินกันทั้งนั้น
It helps with digestion.
ช่วยย่อยดี
Here.
อะ
Thank you, Mom.
ขอบคุณครับแม่
Dad.
พ่อครับ
How is Mom's health lately?
ช่วงนี้แม่สุขภาพเป็นไงบ้างครับ
It's quite good.
ก็ดีนะ
Last time,
แค่ครั้งก่อน
she got
อาจจะ
a bit scared.
ตกใจไปหน่อย
But it was a good thing too.
แต่ก็ดีเหมือนกัน
Now, she's more health-conscious.
เดี๋ยวนี้รู้จักดูแลสุขภาพแล้ว
Less salt, less oil, less sugar.
เค็มน้อย มันน้อย หวานน้อย
I have no choice.
พ่อเลยต้อง
I can only buy
แอบออกไปข้างนอก
some pork head meat outside
กินพวกหัวหมูบ้าง
to nourish myself a bit.
จะได้บำรุงหน่อย
Where did you get personal money to buy that?
พ่อมีเงินส่วนตัวด้วยเหรอเนี่ย
I've been saving it for dozens of years.
แอบซุกมาสิบกว่าปี
Of course there's no problem.
พอมีอยู่แล้ว
You've been hiding personal money for dozens of years?
แอบซุกเงินมาสิบกว่าปีด้วยเหรอเนี่ย
Our son is back.
ลูกชายกลับมาทั้งที
I'm just bluffing in front of him.
ผมขอโม้บ้างไม่ได้หรือไง
Don't take it seriously.
ก็แค่ล้อเล่น
Save it.
ไม่ต้องมามุกนี้เลย
Come on, come out.
มานี่ ๆ ออกมา มานี่เลย
Come on.
มา
I'm washing the dishes.
ผมล้างจานอยู่
Can't our son wash them?
ลูกล้างไม่เป็นหรือไง
Mom.
แม่ครับ
I can wash them.
ผมล้างได้ครับ
Dad's going out.
พ่อกำลังออกไปครับ
(Champion)
(เกียรติบัตร ถ้วยรางวัล)
(Sixth International Math Olympiad First Place)
(รางวัลชนะเลิศ โอลิมปิกคณิตศาสตร์)
(Math)
(คณิตศาสตร์)
Yu Tu.
อวี๋ถู
Teach me Math.
นายสอนเลขฉันนะ
I'll buy you fried chicken.
ฉันเลี้ยงไก่กรอบนาย
Yu Tu.
อวี๋ถูจ๊ะ
Have some fruits.
กินผลไม้หน่อย
Isn't that your book from senior high?
นี่มันหนังสือตอนม.ปลายนี่
Why do you think about
ทำไมอยู่ ๆ หยิบเล่มนี้
reading it now?
ออกมาดูล่ะ
It's nothing.
ไม่มีอะไรครับ
Why are my books from senior high still here?
ทำไมหนังสือม.ปลายยังอยู่อีกล่ะครับ
They must have been
ก็คงลืมทิ้งไว้
left behind when I was sorting them.
ตอนเก็บบ้านน่ะสิ
There are so many of them.
เยอะขนาดนี้เชียว
Mom.
แม่ครับ
Where's my old computer?
คอมพิวเตอร์เครื่องแรกของผมล่ะครับ
I thought you wouldn't use it anymore,
แม่คิดว่าลูกคงไม่ใช้แล้ว
so I placed it downstairs
ก็เลยเอาไปเก็บ
in that small storage room.
ในห้องเก็บของข้างล่าง
This computer is already so old.
คอมพิวเตอร์เก่าขนาดนี้แล้ว
Why do you think
วันนี้นึกยังไง
about taking it out today?
ถึงเอาออกมาอีกล่ะ
When we replaced our television before,
คราวก่อนที่เปลี่ยนโทรทัศน์
I should have let those people
แม่ก็น่าจะให้พวกเขา
take it away too.
ขนไปด้วยเลย
It's just taking up space anyway,
เก็บไว้ก็เปลืองพื้นที่
but it won't sell for much either.
แต่ขายก็ได้เงินไม่เท่าไหร่
Mom, let's keep it.
แม่ครับ เก็บไว้ก่อนเถอะครับ
Okay, we'll keep it.
ได้ เก็บไว้ก็ได้
(Jade Rabbit Pounding Elixir)
(กระต่ายหยกตำยา)
He accepted it so quickly.
รับเร็วขนาดนี้เชียว
What should I say?
ฉันจะพูดอะไรดีเนี่ย
(Hi.)
(มือเด็ดดวงดาว) (สวัสดีค่ะ)
(I saw your QQ account)
(ฉันเห็นชื่อ QQ ของคุณ)
(in the aerospace forum,)
(ในกระทู้อวกาศ)
(so I added you.)
(ก็เลยแอดมา)
(The one about Chang'e 1?)
(ยานอวกาศฉางเอ๋อ 1 เหรอครับ)
(Your discussion is so interesting.)
(เห็นที่พวกคุณคุยกันน่าสนใจมาก)
(Do you think we can really)
(คุณคิดว่าพวกเรา)
(go to the moon?)
(จะไปเหยียบดวงจันทร์ได้จริง ๆ เหรอคะ)
(It's just a matter of time and desire.)
(เป็นแค่เรื่องของเวลากับความตั้งใจ)
(In the future,)
(วันหลังถ้ามีคำถาม)
(can I consult you about some questions?)
(ฉันขอถามคุณได้ไหมคะ)
(Actually, I'm just a beginner.)
(ที่จริงฉันเป็นพวกหน้าใหม่)
(I've just started taking an interest in this.)
(เพิ่งจะเริ่มสนใจเอง)
(Sure.)
(ได้ครับ)
(Thank you.)
(ขอบคุณค่ะ)
(I have a question.)
(มีคำถามหนึ่ง)
(How fast should the probe be)
(ยานสำรวจต้องใช้ความเร็วเท่าไหร่)
(in order to break away from the Earth's gravity?)
(ถึงจะพ้นจากแรงดึงดูดของโลกคะ)
(You can search for that on Baidu.)
(คำถามนี้คุณเสิร์ชหาเอาเองได้)
(Oh, okay.)
(อ๋อ ได้ค่ะ)
I'm doomed.
จบกัน
He must have figured out
เขาจะต้องรู้แน่ ๆ
that I don't know anything.
ว่าฉันไม่รู้เรื่องอะไรเลย
(I understand now.)
(ฉันเจอแล้วค่ะ)
(But I think it's not quite the same)
(แต่เหมือนว่าถ้าไปดวงจันทร์)
(on the moon, right?)
(จะไม่เหมือนกันเท่าไหร่)
(Because the moon is the Earth's satellite.)
(เพราะว่าดวงจันทร์เป็นดาวบริวารของโลก)
(Hello.)
(ฮัลโหล ฮัลโหล)
(Last time, I asked if I could consult you)
(ครั้งก่อนที่บอกว่า)
(about some questions. Can I still do that?)
(ถ้ามีคำถามให้ถามคุณ ยังถามได้อยู่ไหมคะ)
(I saw your forum discussion)
(ฉันเห็นที่พวกคุณคุยกันในกระทู้)
(about the gap between our nation's and USA's aerospace technology.)
(เรื่องเทคโนโลยีอวกาศ ของอเมริกากับจีนยังต่างกัน)
(Is the gap between us)
(พวกเรากับพวกเขา)
(really that huge?)
(ยังห่างกันขนาดนั้นเชียวเหรอ)
He's not replying again.
ไม่ตอบอีกแล้ว
(Are you there?)
(อยู่ไหมเอ่ย อยู่ไหม)
(Could it be that you've deleted me?)
(ลบฉันทิ้งแล้วเหรอ)
When will you take the initiative
เมื่อไหร่ถึงจะเริ่ม
to talk to me?
คุยกับฉันก่อนบ้างเนี่ย
(The group chat discussion is so lively.)
(ในกลุ่มคุยกันสนุกจัง)
(Do you think mankind can really)
(คุณคิดว่ามนุษย์จะสามารถ)
(migrate to Mars?)
(ย้ายไปอยู่ดาวอังคารได้จริง ๆ ไหม)
(We have a new member.)
(มีคนเข้ามาใหม่เหรอ)
(I think so.)
(เหมือนจะใช่นะ)
(And it's a girl.)
(เป็นผู้หญิงด้วย)
(Hello.)
(สวัสดีค่ะทุกคน)
(It's really a girl.)
(ผู้หญิงจริง ๆ ด้วย)
(Did someone invite her?)
(ใครลากเพื่อนเข้ามาหรือเปล่าเนี่ย)
(No.)
(ไม่ใช่ค่ะ)
(I saw your group ID on the aerospace forum,)
(ฉันเห็นชื่อกลุ่มในกระทู้อวกาศ)
(so I joined.)
(ก็เลยตามเข้ามาค่ะ)
(Miss, how old are you?)
(น้องสาว อายุเท่าไหร่จ๊ะ)
(Every sentence has an emoticon.)
(พิมพ์ทุกคำต้องใส่อิโมติคอนตลอดเลย)
(17.)
(สิบเจ็ดค่ะ)
(You're so young.)
(เด็กจัง)
(You must still be in senior high.)
(ยังเรียนม.ปลายอยู่ใช่ไหม)
(Senior high students nowadays are incredible.)
(เดี๋ยวนี้เด็กม.ปลายเก่งจังเลยนะ)
(We have a senior high student in our group too.)
(ในกลุ่มเราก็มีเด็กม.ปลายเหมือนกัน)
(He has a lot of knowledge.)
(ความรู้แน่นเอี๊ยด)
(Is he that incredible?)
(เขาเก่งขนาดนั้นเลยเหรอคะ)
(I don't know anything.)
(ฉันไม่รู้อะไรเลย)
(I'm just a bit curious.)
(แค่อยากรู้อยากเห็น)
(It's fine. You're welcome here.)
(ไม่เป็นไร ๆ ต้อนรับหมดแหละ)
(He hasn't joined us lately.)
(ช่วงนี้เขาไม่ค่อยมาเท่าไหร่)
(I'll introduce you two when he joins us.)
(ถ้าเขามาแล้วจะแนะนำให้เธอรู้จัก)
(Galaxy, you're here.)
(ซิงเฉิน มาแล้วเหรอ)
(In the afternoon, you missed)
(อดเจอคนอายุเท่าเธอ)
(someone of your age.)
(เมื่อตอนบ่ายเลย)
(I were here.)
(ยังอยู่ค่ะ)
(But what you were talking about was so professional.)
(แต่พวกคุณคุยกันลึกมากเลย)
(I didn't dare to speak.)
(ฉันไม่กล้าคุย)
(But he's really incredible.)
(แต่เขาเก่งจริง ๆ ค่ะ)
(He knows a lot of things.)
(รู้อะไรเยอะเลย)
(Is anyone here)
(มีพี่ ๆ ในห้อง)
(who can help me?)
(พอช่วยได้ไหมคะ)
(I have a physics problem that I can't answer.)
(โจทย์ฟิสิกส์ข้อนี้ทำยังไงคะ)
(So that's how it's done.)
(แบบนี้เองเหรอคะ)
(Thank you, Mr. Fish Head.)
(ขอบคุณพี่อวี๋โถวนะคะ)
(You're so incredible.)
(เก่งจังเลยค่ะ)
(Mr. Fish Head.)
(พี่อวี๋โถวคะ)
(My teacher said)
(ที่พี่แก้โจทย์ให้เมื่อวาน)
(that your solution from yesterday was wrong.)
(คุณครูบอกว่าผิดค่ะ)
(I can't join you anymore.)
(หลังจากนี้ฉันมาเล่นไม่ได้แล้วนะคะ)
(Why? Your parents won't allow it?)
(ทำไมล่ะ พ่อแม่ห้ามเหรอ)
(No.)
(ไม่ใช่ค่ะ)
(I must study hard now.)
(ฉันจะตั้งใจอ่านหนังสือ)
(After getting into my target university,)
(ไว้ฉันจะสอบเข้ามหาลัย ที่อยากเข้าได้เมื่อไหร่)
(I'll come to join you again.)
(ค่อยมาคุยเล่นใหม่นะคะ)
(Which one is your target?)
(เธออยากเข้ามหาลัยไหนเหรอ)
(Tsinghua.)
(ชิงหัว)
(Nice.)
(เจ๋งนะเนี่ย)
(You can't judge a book by its cover, girl.)
(คนเราอย่าดูกันแต่ภายนอก น้องสาว)
(You have a high ambition.)
(มีความมุ่งมั่นนะเนี่ย)
(Actually, I don't have a high ambition.)
(ที่จริงฉันก็ไม่ได้มุ่งมั่นอะไรหรอกค่ะ)
(But lately,)
(ก็แค่เร็ว ๆ นี้)
(I confessed my feelings to the person I like.)
(ฉันเพิ่งสารภาพรักไป)
(I think he feels like my grades aren't good enough,)
(แต่เหมือนเขารังเกียจที่ฉันคะแนนไม่ดี)
(so I want to get)
(ฉันก็เลย)
(into the same university as him.)
(อยากสอบเข้าที่เดียวกับเขา)
(Perhaps he'll like me then.)
(ไม่แน่เขาอาจจะชอบฉันก็ได้)
(That's not what men look at.)
(ผู้ชายไม่สนเรื่องพวกนี้หรอก)
(Hand-picked Stars.)
(เด็ดดาว)
(Are you not that beautiful?)
(เธอสวยไม่พอหรือเปล่า)
(I am very beautiful.)
(ฉันสวยมาก)
(Keep a low profile.)
(ถ่อมตัวหน่อย)
(Anyway, I keep thinking about it,)
(ถึงยังไงที่ฉันลองคิดดู)
(and the reason should be that my grades)
(ก็มีแต่คะแนนฉันที่ดีไม่พอ)
(aren't good enough.)
(เท่านั้นแหละ)
(That's why I'm planning to study hard.)
(ก็เลยตั้งใจว่าจะขยันสักหน่อย)
(But my grades are actually)
(ที่จริงคะแนนของฉัน)
(around top 200 in the city.)
(ก็ติดท็อปสองร้อยของเมืองนะ)
(But he's always)
(แต่ว่าเขาต่างหาก)
(number one in the city.)
(ได้ที่หนึ่งของเมืองตลอดเลย)
(You can do it.)
(เจ๋ง)
(That is a big gap.)
(ห่างกันเยอะนะเนี่ย)
♪You crossed the sea of ​​stars and came with light♪
♪เธอข้ามผ่านหมู่ดวงดาว มาพร้อมกับแสงสว่าง♪
(I think I can study harder.)
(ฉันคิดว่าจะลองขยันดูสักตั้ง)
♪My heart is like the dust, and I couldn't bear to stain the hemline♪
♪หัวใจฉันเปรียบเหมือนฝุ่น ไม่อยากแปดเปื้อนกระโปรงของเธอ♪
♪To love in a different way, the fireworks are in the stars' good graces♪
♪ความรักที่ไม่เหมือนใคร ดอกไม้ไฟที่ดวงดาวยังชายตามอง♪
If I could get into Tsinghua too,
ถ้าฉันสอบเข้าชิงหัวได้
then I'd be one of the celebrities in the showbiz
ฉันก็จะเป็นนักแสดงที่เรียนเก่งที่สุด
who has a very incredible educational background.
ในวงการบันเทิงคนหนึ่ง
If your fans knew
ถ้าแฟนคลับเธอรู้ว่า
that you want to get into Tsinghua for their sakes,
เธอคิดจะสอบเข้าชิงหัวเพื่อพวกเขา
they would be very happy.
ก็จะต้องดีใจมากแน่ ๆ
♪Even the fireworks desire to give the stars a future♪
♪ดอกไม้ไฟอยากเป็นที่พึ่งพิงให้ดวงดาว♪
It's not because of them.
ไม่ใช่เพื่อพวกเขาหรอก
♪As long as you are around♪
♪ขอเพียงแค่มีเธออยู่♪
I was quite surprised that you chose Finance
ที่นายสอบเข้าสายการเงิน
as your major for your college application
ฉันยังประหลาดใจมากเลย
I've always remembered that your dream
จำได้ว่าความฝันของนาย
is the galaxy.
คือทะเลดาวนี่
I'm planning to give up
เพราะฉันไม่สนใจ
on the galaxy.
ทะเลดาวแล้ว
♪The light in your eyes dimmed♪
♪มองดูนัยน์ตาของเธอ แสงไฟค่อย ๆ เลือนหาย♪
♪I laughed at myself and that I deserve it ♪
♪ทำได้แต่สมน้ำหน้าตัวเอง♪
♪My heart skips a beat♪
(เมื่อก่อนนายเคยบอกว่านายจะเปลี่ยนอาชีพ)
that you wanted to give up?
ทำไมล่ะ
Is it because of your family?
หรือว่าเป็นเพราะครอบครัว
But I remember that your uncle
แต่ฉันจำได้ว่า
is also working in aerospace.
ลุงของนายก็ทำเกี่ยวกับอวกาศ
Why are your parents against it?
ทำไมพ่อแม่นายถึงไม่เห็นด้วยล่ะ
Because you've always gotten a perfect score
เพราะทั้งวิชาคณิต ฟิสิกส์
in math and physics.
นายคะแนนเต็มตลอด
Back then, I thought,
ตอนนั้นฉันคิดอยู่ว่า
"He'll probably become
เพื่อนคนนี้
a very incredible scientist in the future.
ที่เก่งกาจมาก
I'll feel very honored too."
ฉันคงรู้สึกภาคภูมิใจไปด้วย
I just wanted to defend you.
ฉันแค่อยากพูดแทนนาย
I want you to continue being an aerospace engineer
ฉันเป็นคนที่อยากให้นาย
more than anyone.
เป็นวิศวกรอวกาศต่อไป
Why?
เพราะอะไร
♪I can run toward the future with you♪
♪ที่ฉันจะได้จับมือเธอพุ่งทะยานไป♪
I'll never ask you why again.
ฉันจะไม่ถามนายอีก
Yu.
เหล่าอวี๋
You just like dilly-dallying.
ชักช้าอยู่นั่นแหละ
Yu, hurry up.
เหล่าอวี๋ เร็วเข้าสิ
We're going out for a walk.
ออกมาเดินเล่น
Why do you have a thermos with you?
หยิบแก้วเก็บความร้อนมาทำไมเนี่ย
Zhang called me just now
เหล่าจางเพิ่งโทรมาหาฉัน
to play mahjong with him.
ชวนไปเล่นไพ่
Mahjong... You just keep playing mahjong.
เล่นไพ่เล่นไพ่ เล่นได้ทุกวัน
Our son is home,
ลูกชายกลับมาทั้งที
and you're still playing mahjong.
ยังจะไปเล่นไพ่อีก
I've already spent a few hours
ฉันก็อยู่กับเขา
with him.
ตั้งหลายชั่วโมงแล้วนี่
Fine.
ก็ได้
Come back before 9 p.m.
กลับมาก่อนสามทุ่มนะ
I will.
ได้เลยจ้ะ
Take good care of your mom.
ดูแลแม่ด้วยนะ
You keep playing mahjong.
เล่นไพ่ได้ทั้งวัน
Your son is home?
ลูกชายกลับมาแล้วเหรอ
Yes, he just arrived at lunch time.
ค่ะ ตอนบ่ายเพิ่งถึง
Yu Tu
อวี๋ถูของเธอเนี่ย
is becoming more and more handsome.
หล่อขึ้นทุกวันเลยนะ
Does he have a girlfriend now?
มีแฟนหรือยัง
He's too busy with work to think about that.
งานยุ่งมากค่ะ เลยยังไม่มี
No matter how busy he is,
จะยุ่งแค่ไหน
he can't delay marriage.
เรื่องสำคัญในชีวิตจะไม่สนใจไม่ได้นะ
That's the disadvantage
ทำงานต่างเมือง
of working far away.
ก็ไม่ดีอย่างนี้แหละ
The parents can't interfere in his business.
พ่อแม่ดูแลไม่ได้
If he worked here,
ถ้าทำงานแถวนี้นะ
his kids would already be in school.
ป่านนี้ลูกเข้าโรงเรียนได้แล้ว
Right.
ก็ใช่น่ะสิคะ
Let me see
เดี๋ยวไว้ฉันถามให้
if there's anyone in Shanghai
ว่ามีใครที่เซี่ยงไฮ้
that I can help introduce to you later.
ที่จะแนะนำให้ได้หรือเปล่า
Don't forget.
อย่าลืมนะคะ
Bye.
บ๊ายบาย
Come on.
ไปเถอะ ๆ
That lady just likes to worry about people.
คุณป้าคนนี้เป็นอย่างนี้แหละ
Tell me.
บอกแม่หน่อยซิ
In the afternoon,
ว่าตอนบ่าย
was something bothering you?
มีเรื่องไม่สบายใจหรือเปล่า
Before I came home last time,
ก่อนกลับบ้านครั้งที่แล้ว
I had tendered my resignation,
ผมบอกที่ทำงานว่าจะลาออก
but I have still gone back there now.
แต่ตอนนี้กลับไปทำที่เดิมแล้วครับ
I think
แม่ก็รู้สึกว่า
that you're like your uncle the most.
ลูกน่ะเหมือนลุงที่สุด
You've always admired him since you were little.
ลูกชื่นชมเขาตั้งแต่เด็ก
You kept boasting to your friends saying,
ชอบโม้กับเพื่อน ๆ ว่า
"My uncle is
ลุงของฉันเนี่ย
in charge of rocket launches."
เป็นคนยิงจรวดนะ
Among my siblings,
ในบรรดาพี่น้องของแม่
your uncle is the smartest.
ลุงเขาเก่งที่สุด
But he also has the hardest time.
แต่ก็ลำบากที่สุดเหมือนกัน
He's all alone in the northwest of China.
อยู่ต้าซีเป่ยคนเดียว [*ซีเป่ย : ภาคตะวันตกเฉียงเหนือ]
He can't take care of his family at all.
ดูแลครอบครัวไม่ได้เลย
One time,
มีอยู่ครั้งหนึ่ง
your grandpa was sick
คุณตาไม่สบาย
and almost didn't make it.
เกือบจะไม่รอดแล้ว
We couldn't contact him no matter how hard we tried.
ทำยังไงก็ติดต่อเขาไม่ได้
Back then,
ตอนนั้นนะ
communications weren't as advanced
การสื่อสารก็ยังไม่พัฒนา
as it is now.
เหมือนสมัยนี้
Later on, we were finally
แต่สุดท้าย
able to save your grandpa.
ก็ช่วยคุณตาเอาไว้ได้
We got into contact with your uncle.
พอติดต่อลุงของลูกได้แล้ว
We wanted him to come home,
พวกเราอยากให้เขากลับมา
but he spoke haltingly for a while,
เขาทำอ้ำอึ้งอยู่ตั้งนาน
and said that he couldn't.
แล้วก็บอกว่าไม่ได้
He said
เขาบอกว่า
that since your grandpa was fine now,
ในเมื่อคุณตาไม่เป็นอะไรแล้ว
his current mission was also very important.
แล้วตอนนี้เขามีภารกิจที่สำคัญมาก
He could only come home after completing his mission.
ต้องเสร็จภารกิจก่อนถึงกลับมาได้
And he ended up
แล้วยังไง
coming home only after one month.
อีกเดือนหนึ่งกว่าเขาจะกลับมา
All of his siblings
พวกพี่น้องของแม่เนี่ย
were mad at him
พากันโกรธเขา
and treated him coldly.
ทำเย็นชาใส่เขา
Back then,
ตอนนั้น
your grandaunt
มีคุณป้าคนหนึ่ง
came to visit him,
มาเยี่ยม
and pointed at him and scolded him
ถึงกับชี้หน้าด่าเขาเลย
for being unfilial.
ด่าว่าอกตัญญู
Your uncle just listened
ลุงของลูกก็ได้แต่ฟัง
and didn't say a word.
ไม่พูดอะไรเลย
You were still so little back then.
ตอนนั้นลูกยังเด็กมาก
You suddenly said,
อยู่ ๆ ก็พูดขึ้นมาว่า
"Grandaunt,
ป้าครับ
isn't your son
ลูกชายของป้าทำงาน
working in the USA?"
ที่อเมริกาใช่ไหมครับ
Your grandaunt
ป้าของลูก
loved hearing that the most.
ฟังแล้วก็ดีใจ
She said, "Right.
ก็พูดว่า
Yu Tu,
ใช่ ๆ อวี๋ถู
study hard too,
หลานต้องตั้งใจเรียนนะ
and go to the USA in the future."
จะได้ไปอเมริกาเหมือนกัน
Then you said,
แต่ลูกกลับบอกว่า
"Grandaunt,
ป้าครับ
your son
ถ้าอย่างนั้นพี่เขา
hasn't visited you for so many years.
อยู่อเมริกาตั้งนานไม่กลับมาหาป้าเลย
Why don't you scold him for being unfilial?"
ทำไมป้าไม่ว่าเขาอกตัญญูบ้างล่ะครับ
Back then, I thought,
ตอนนั้นแม่ก็เลยคิดได้
"Hey.
ว่า
They both
ทั้งสองคน
can't be with their parents.
ไม่ได้คอยอยู่ดูแลพ่อแม่เหมือนกัน
If you live abroad,
คนทำงานต่างประเทศ
people envy you.
มีแต่คนอิจฉา
If you're in the northwest of China,
ส่วนคนที่อยู่ต้าซีเป่ย
and silently making your contribution,
อุทิศตัวอยู่เงียบ ๆ
people would say that it's not worth it,
กลับมีแต่คนว่าไม่คุ้ม
and even consider you unfilial.
แถมยังว่าอกตัญญู
Does that make sense?"
มันใช้ได้ที่ไหน
All of us adults
ผู้ใหญ่ตั้งหลายคนที่อยู่ตรงนั้น
couldn't figure it out.
กลับคิดไม่ได้
We were no better than a ten-year-old child like you.
สู้เด็กสิบขวบอย่างลูกไม่ได้เลย
I've been smart since I was little.
ผมฉลาดแต่เด็ก
Of course.
ก็ใช่น่ะสิ
You're my son.
ลูกแม่นี่นา
Son.
ลูกจ๊ะ
You know
หลักการชีวิตเนี่ย
about life's truths.
รู้หมดแหละ
But when it comes to yourself,
แต่พอเป็นเรื่องตัวเอง
you're confused.
กลับคิดไม่ได้
Actually, the thing I regret the most
ที่จริงในชีวิตแม่
in my life
มีเรื่องเสียใจที่สุด
is forcing you to choose Finance
ก็ตอนที่ลูกสอบเข้ามหาวิทยาลัย
as your major
แม่บังคับให้ลูกเรียน
for your college application.
ด้านการเงิน
What was I thinking back then?
ตอนนั้นแม่คิดอะไรน่ะเหรอ
I thought,
แม่ก็คิดว่า
"My son has such high grades.
ลูกแม่คะแนนสูงขนาดนั้น
He must go
ก็ต้องสอบเข้า
into the most popular major.
คณะที่ฮิตที่สุด
Otherwise, his grades would be wasted."
ไม่อย่างนั้นก็เสียดายคะแนนแย่
Later on,
พอมาทีหลัง
I found out
แม่ได้รู้ว่า
that you secretly studied two majors.
ลูกแอบเรียนควบสองคณะ
I regretted it so much.
แม่รู้สึกผิดเลย
Because of me,
เป็นเพราะแม่
you wasted so much effort.
ลูกต้องเสียเวลาไปตั้งเท่าไหร่
It's all my fault.
เพราะแม่คนเดียว
Son.
ลูกจ๊ะ
Be honest with me.
บอกแม่มาตามตรง
Were you planning to resign
ที่ลูกจะลาออก
because of my illness
เป็นเพราะว่า
last time?
ครั้งก่อนที่แม่ป่วยใช่ไหม
Mom.
แม่ครับ
You're so silly.
ลูกเนี่ยนะ
You were overthinking.
คิดมากอีกแล้ว
No matter what you do in the future,
วันหลังไม่ว่าจะเรื่องอะไร
don't think
ไม่ต้องคิดถึงว่า
about us.
พวกเราจะเป็นยังไงเลย
Just think about yourself.
ดูแลตัวเองก็พอ
Son.
ลูกจ๊ะ
I'm really proud of you.
แม่ภูมิใจในตัวลูกจริง ๆ
You're already doing very well.
ลูกทำได้เยี่ยมมาก ๆ แล้ว
Your dad and I
มีแต่คนอิจฉา
are envied by people so much.
แม่กับพ่อ
Promise me.
รับปากแม่นะ
There's really no need
ไม่จำเป็นต้อง
to be the best in everything.
ทำทุกเรื่องให้ดีที่สุดหรอกนะ
Son.
นี่ลูก
You must consider getting married too.
เรื่องคู่ครองก็ต้องรีบคิดแล้วนะ
Otherwise, those ladies
ไม่อย่างนั้นป้า ๆ พวกนั้น
would keep asking me,
จะคอยถามแม่อยู่เรื่อย
"When will Yu Tu
ว่าอวี๋ถูของแม่
get married?"
เมื่อไหร่จะแต่งงาน
Her qualifications don't need to be too good.
ไม่ต้องมีเงื่อนไขเยอะ
She doesn't need to be very beautiful.
ไม่ต้องสวยมากหรอก
It's best if she knows how to take care of people.
แค่ดูแลคนอื่นเป็นก็พอ
Mom.
แม่ครับ
I think I like the opposite of that.
ที่ผมชอบมันตรงข้ามกันเลย
(Dunhuang)
(ตุนหวง)
I'm sorry.
ขอโทษนะครับ
My flight got delayed.
เครื่องบินดีเลย์
I've already gotten off the plane.
ผมลงเครื่องแล้ว
Okay.
ครับ
I'll be right there.
ใกล้ถึงแล้วครับ
Hello.
สวัสดีครับ
I'm Yu Tu from Base 158.
ผมอวี๋ถูจากหนึ่งห้าแปด
The van for your institute
รถของทีมพวกคุณ
is already full.
เต็มแล้วครับ
Didn't you fly here together?
คุณไม่ได้มาด้วยกันเหรอ
I flew here from another place.
ผมบินมาจากที่อื่น
Take the last van then.
งั้นคุณนั่งคันสุดท้ายแล้วกัน
Just wait for a few more colleagues
พวกเรารอให้
from the Chinese Academy of Sciences,
ทีมจากศูนย์อวกาศมาถึง
and you can leave.
ก็ออกเดินทางกันได้
Thank you.
ขอบคุณครับ
You're welcome.
ไม่เป็นไรครับ
Hi.
สวัสดีครับ
We're from the Chinese Academy of Sciences. What about you?
พวกเรามาจากศูนย์อวกาศ คุณล่ะ
Mr. Zhou?
คุณโจว
How...
คุณ
How did you know?
คุณรู้ได้ยังไง
We had a teleconference before.
เราเคยประชุมออนไลน์กัน
I'm Yu Tu from Base 158.
ผมอวี๋ถูจากหนึ่งห้าแปดครับ
I heard from the people
ผมได้ยินทีมที่เคย
who joined the Field Experiment Team before
ร่วมการทดลองภาคสนามบอกว่า
that food in the base is very good.
ของกินที่นี่อร่อยมาก
They even hired
มีพ่อครัวทำลาเมี่ยน [*ลาเมี่ยน : บะหมี่เส้นดึง ของขึ้นชื่อซีเป่ย]
a ramen master.
เส้นสดด้วย
After hearing that,
ผมได้ยินแค่นี้
I've been so looking forward to it.
ก็เฝ้ารอให้ถึงตอนนี้เลย
Why do you always
คุณเนี่ยนะ
keep thinking about food?
คิดแต่เรื่องกินตลอด
I'm from the north.
ผมคนทางเหนือ
We love noodles.
ชอบกินแป้งกินเส้นอยู่แล้ว
Mr. Yu.
คุณอวี๋
You're from the south, aren't you?
คุณมาจากทางใต้ใช่ไหม
Will that be different from what you're used to?
จะกินได้รึเปล่า
No.
ไม่เป็นไรครับ
It's fine as long as I get full.
ขอแค่อิ่มก็พอ
Mr. Yu is handsome.
คุณอวี๋หน้าตาดี
When he speaks,
แค่เปิดปากพูด
he sounds like a guy in the technology field indeed.
ก็รู้เลยว่าเป็นหนุ่มสายวิทย์
Right.
นั่นน่ะสิ
♪When the sun shines♪
♪เมื่ออาทิตย์ผ่านพ้นโลกไป♪
♪On the other side of the earth♪
♪สู่ความเวิ้งว้างอีกครึ่งหนึ่ง♪
♪Please wake me up♪
♪ช่วยปลุกฉันด้วยนะ♪
♪I want to see the dawn♪
♪ฉันจะไปดูแสงแห่งรุ่งอรุณ♪
♪During autumn when frost falls♪
♪เมื่อหิมะตกในฤดูใบไม้ร่วง♪
♪In the warmest place♪
♪ในที่ที่อบอุ่นที่สุด♪
♪Please wake me up♪
♪ช่วยปลุกฉันด้วยนะ♪
♪I want to be like it♪
♪ฉันอยากเป็นเหมือนหิมะ♪
♪Scattering in the golden fallen leaves♪
♪ลอยล่องสู่กลางใบไม้สีทอง♪
♪Blending with the mud♪
♪รวมเป็นหนึ่งเดียวกับก้อนดิน♪
♪Falling into the vast sky♪
♪กลิ้งลงสู่ทะเลที่เส้นขอบฟ้า♪
♪Dissipating with the morning light♪
♪ระเหยไปพร้อมกับแสงแรกของตะวัน♪
We're here.
ถึงแล้วนี่
Guys.
ทุกท่าน
We'll be living here for a month.
นี่คือที่ที่พวกเราต้องอยู่กันหนึ่งเดือน
♪Born as an eagle♪
♪เกิดเป็นอินทรี♪
♪With wide wings♪
♪กางปีกคลุมฟ้า♪
♪Why lower your head and learn to crawl♪
♪ไม่ต้องก้มหน้าหัดคลาน♪
♪Rising♪
♪ทะยานขึ้นไป♪
♪The high clouds♪
♪เหนือหมู่เมฆอันกว้างใหญ่♪
♪The raging fire is swaying in my eyes♪
♪เปลวไฟโชติช่วง คุกรุ่นนัยน์ตา♪
♪I was born as an eagle♪
♪เกิดเป็นอินทรี♪
♪Flying against the wind♪
♪บินล่องทวนลม♪
Sirs.
ทุกท่านครับ
There's a strong sandstorm in the base.
ที่นี่ลมแรงมาก
Protect yourself well before getting off the van.
ป้องกันให้ดีค่อยลงจากรถนะ
Well...
ทางทีม
We're from the Telemetry Team.
ทดสอบระยะไกล
Turn right ahead.
ข้างหน้าเลี้ยวขวา
It's up ahead?
ข้างหน้าใช่ไหม
Right.
ครับ ๆ
Register here.
ตรงนี้ ลงทะเบียนก่อน
♪Is my destiny in life♪
♪คือชะตาชีวิตของฉัน♪
Take care.
ค่อย ๆ นะ
♪I dreamed of starlight pulling the sleeves♪
♪ฉันฝันเห็นแสงดาวระยิบระยับ บนชายแขนเสื้อ♪
♪A white top covering the thin shoulders♪
♪ชุดสีขาว ปกคลุมหัวไหล่อันซูบเซียว♪
♪I have seen the wounds healed with each passing year♪
♪ฉันเห็นกาลเวลาเยียวยาบาดแผลได้♪
♪There will always be people running towards eternity♪
♪อย่างไรก็มีคนไล่ตามชั่วฟ้าดินสลาย♪
♪The bustling intersection♪
♪ท่ามกลางทางแยกผู้คนพลุกพล่าน♪
♪Looking back all of a sudden under the dim light♪
♪แสงไฟริบหรี่ เหลียวหลังมองไป♪
♪I loved your eyes looking at the starry sky♪
♪เคยรักเธอ มองไปยังดาวทอประกายบนฟากฟ้า นัยน์ตาที่สงบนิ่ง♪
♪And I loved the universe in your heart♪
♪ก็เคยรักเธอ ในใจฉันเธอคือทุกอย่าง ในจักรวาล♪
♪Time does not stop, remember the time that we failed to treasure♪
♪กาลเวลาไม่เคยหยุดรอ เก็บซ่อนความเสียใจในสิ่งที่ทำไปตลอดเวลา♪
♪The wind passes by the tall buildings with no one awaiting it♪
♪ลมพัดผ่านตึกสูง ไม่มีใครเฝ้ารออีกต่อไป♪
♪I've dreamed of traveling around the planet♪
♪ฉันก็เคยคิดฝันท่องไปตามดวงดาว♪
♪Seeing the galaxy pass through the clouds♪
♪ผ่านมวลเมฆ ดูทางช้างเผือกที่หลั่งไหล♪
♪I looked at the hills with sorrow♪
♪ฉันเคยมองขุนเขาอย่างเศร้าหมอง♪
♪Will the exit of the dream lead to the end of the starry sky?♪
♪ทางออกแห่งฝัน อยู่ที่สุดขอบทะเลดาวหรือไม่♪
♪Looking back all of a sudden♪
♪เหลียวหลังมองไป♪
♪Which galaxy am I drifting on?♪
♪ฉันล่องลอยอยู่บนทะเลดาวสายไหนกัน♪
♪Looking into the distance, which of the stars are your eyes?♪
♪เฝ้ามองว่าดาวดวงไหนคือนัยน์ตาเธอ♪
♪It's out of reach, so dazzling and hard to get♪
♪ดาวระยิบระยับ เอื้อมไม่ถึงครอบครองไม่ได้♪
♪Time does not hold back, the spring and autumn in the passing time♪
♪กาลเวลาไม่รอใคร เมื่อเวลาผ่าน สรรพสิ่งก็เปลี่ยนไป อดีตจบสิ้นลง♪
♪The wind sings the song of freedom as I listen to the tenderness of time♪
♪สายลมขับร้องอิสรภาพ ฉันตั้งใจฟังความอ่อนโยนของกาลเวลา♪